<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Ben Chinn</title>
 <link href="http://benchinn.com/blog/feed/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://benchinn.com/"/>
 <updated>2011-08-23T11:28:17-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://benchinn.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Ben Chinn</name>
   <email>ben@chinn.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Tools</title>
   <link href="http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/14/tools.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/14/tools</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tools are important. I once spent 6 months renovating a house and although I didn&amp;#8217;t really know what was doing I was lucky enough to be working with somebody who did. This is the advice she gave me: use the right tool for the job and make sure your body is in the right position when you&amp;#8217;re using it. Following this advice got me through many home improvement tasks efficiently and without injury. Surely it&amp;#8217;s a different story when we&amp;#8217;re talking about knowledge work though, right? Let&amp;#8217;s see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='use_the_right_tool_for_the_job'&gt;Use the right tool for the job&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even for those of use sitting in an office in front of a computer screen all day this is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows or Mac or Linux?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Vim or Emacs or Textmate or &lt;span&gt;insert other editor here&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sitting or standing?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Subversion or Git?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are meaninful questions and the answers make a difference. Everybody in my team at work uses a Mac. I believe this gives my work environment a different character from the offices I&amp;#8217;ve worked in where folks were on difference platforms or were all on Windows machines. I think it&amp;#8217;s that my team feels less &amp;#8220;corporate&amp;#8221; even though we work within a corporate environment. Are Macs better? Maybe. What&amp;#8217;s for certain is that they evoke a different response in their users and they are more conducive to certain kinds of work. As Doug Rushkoff argues in his book, &lt;a href='http://www.orbooks.com/our-books/program/'&gt;Program or Be Programmed&lt;/a&gt; technologies have biases that we generally take for granted. Using the right technology means making these biases work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='put_your_body_in_the_right_position'&gt;Put your body in the right position&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This comes down to using the tool correctly. If you &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; vim but find you&amp;#8217;re spending half your day creating macros then maybe you need an editor that gives you less opportunity to fiddle. If you&amp;#8217;ve got 100 emails in your inbox each of which you read every time a new message comes in then maybe you should be taking a different attitude toward your mail application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this being said, what are the tools that I use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A iMac at home and MacBook Pro in the office.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Transmit, iTerm2 for web development.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Safari and Chrome for web browsing.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Apple Mail.app for work emails, Sparrow for personal messages through gmail. I&amp;#8217;ve been going back and forth from Mailplane and Sparrow and am still not sure what fits me best.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;TextExpander, Keyboard Maestro and Launchbar. These three help me automate or speed a bunch of tasks I perform every day.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Omnifocus for task management&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;iPhone and iPad. I use calendar and address book almost exclusively on iOS rather than the mac.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Multiple tools for writing and coding. Textmate is the heavy hitter in this department and I&amp;#8217;ll second those who say that even with its flaws and lack of visible development it still does a terrific job. I also use Nvalt for tracking text files on the Mac and a bunch of apps on iOS: Simplenote, Notesy and Writing Kit top the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to post more about some of these tools and how to make the best of them.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Badonkadonk Land Cruiser/Tank</title>
   <link href="http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/08/the-donk.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/08/the-donk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I first heard about this amazing product on &lt;a href='http://www.thebuglepodcast.com/' title='The Bugle - Audio Newspaper For A Visual World'&gt;the bugle podcast&lt;/a&gt; (if you&amp;#8217;re not listening to it every week, shame on you) and was instantly fascinated. It can be yours for $20,000.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>You'd have to be nuts not to buy this</title>
   <link href="http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/08/no-words.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/08/no-words</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;File under: Amazing things found on Amazon by mistake. The reviews are a must read.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>iPad Impressions from a New User</title>
   <link href="http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/03/ipad-thoughts.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/03/ipad-thoughts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve had an iPad 2 for almost a week now and while I&amp;#8217;m late to the game I&amp;#8217;m ready to share my impressions. By the way when I say late I mean really late, as in I skipped the first iPad and this is the first one I have owned. My feeling a year ago was that the iPad was a terrific product that would become fully mature with a second release. Given everything I&amp;#8217;ve &lt;a href='http://arstechnica.com/apple/reviews/2011/03/ipad-2-the-ars-review.ars'&gt;read&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='http://daringfireball.net/2011/03/the_ipad_2'&gt;on the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='http://www.suntimes.com/4396870-420/review-ipad-2-is-not-revolutionary-but-it-is-great.html'&gt;subject&lt;/a&gt; it seems that I was correct. I can&amp;#8217;t talk about the increased speed of the iPad 2 or any other improvements over the original but I will give my perspective on the device and how I think I&amp;#8217;ll be using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='just_a_big_iphone'&gt;Just a Big iPhone?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started using the iPad I couldn&amp;#8217;t help but compare it to the iPhone 4 I&amp;#8217;ve had for almost a year. I love how the home screen adjusts with the orientation of the device (unlike the iPhone), I love how the wifi signal stays strong throughout my home (unlike the iPhone) and I like typing on the iPad (unlike the iPhone). I&amp;#8217;m still not sure how much I like reading on the iPad though - even with its much smaller screen the iPhone&amp;#8217;s retina display makes reading more pleasant to my eyes than the iPad&amp;#8217;s pixelated text. No doubt this issue will become moot within another release cycle or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPad impresses me most of all as a &lt;em&gt;computer&lt;/em&gt;. My two year old son calls the iPhone simply &amp;#8220;phone&amp;#8221;. When he first saw the iPad he said &amp;#8220;little &amp;#8216;puter&amp;#8221; (it was adorable, truly). I&amp;#8217;m finding myself using the iPad to do all the things I would usually rather do on my laptop: process email, write notes, visit web sites, etc. In some ways these tasks are even more enjoyable on the iPad especially since I can do them more easily on the sofa without waiting for a computer to start up or shut down when I&amp;#8217;m finished. As I mentioned earlier I&amp;#8217;m even liking typing on the iPad, especially with the benefit of auto correction, which although a mixed bag I&amp;#8217;m still finding more of a help than a hindrance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id='so_close_to_perfection'&gt;So Close to Perfection&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all this gushing I&amp;#8217;ll bring up one quibble. Although it&amp;#8217;s great that the home screens can display properly in landscape mode it&amp;#8217;s a pain that it changes the layout of the icons. For me, recognition of each icon has a lot to do with its relative position on the screen and it&amp;#8217;s confusing for that position to change when I rotate the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sure I&amp;#8217;ll have a lot more to say about the iPad as I continue to use it and learn how it&amp;#8217;s going to fit into my life and workflows. Meanwhile I continue to be inspired by what I feel is the beginning of a real revolution in computing interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Time and Attention</title>
   <link href="http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/03/Time-and-Attention.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/03/Time-and-Attention</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Time is the same, objectively, for everybody. Since time cannot be managed, the only thing that can be managed is our own attention, what are we going to pay attention to, when and for how long. Okay, those are all quantitative concerns but there is also a qualitative element here and that&amp;#8217;s where so many of us fall down. It&amp;#8217;s also something that those in the productivity space are not addressing much although many are hinting at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merlin Mann especially gets very close to talking about this, mostly because he talks so much about his own process. That is in fact pretty much all he talks about. He has made what looks like a full time job talking about writing a book (which I assume is the full time job he is supposed to be pursuing). This is terrific because if gives a real glimpse into the nature of Merlin&amp;#8217;s work process as well as the quality of his thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get back to the quality thing. I suspect that productive folks are not just doing different things but are also doing things differently. I suspect that Merlin has a different experience of his work than I have of mine. He alludes to this when he says that, although Stephen King listens to AC/DC when he writes listening to hard rock will not make you write like Stephen King. Because Stephen King is doing something different when he sits down to write than most of us. Right now I&amp;#8217;m paying attention to what I&amp;#8217;m writing, but my guess is that the &lt;em&gt;quality&lt;/em&gt; of my attention is different than King&amp;#8217;s. I would guess that his focus is deeper and the range of thoughts and feelings he can access at his keyboard is greater (by a long shot) than mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, just the quantitative stuff is hard enough, probably because of the way human beings have evolved to manage our attention. Seth Godin popularly &lt;a href='http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2010/01/quieting-the-lizard-brain.html'&gt;talked about the &amp;#8220;Lizard Brain&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;, the part of us that is &amp;#8220;responsible for fear and rage and reproductive drive&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;hates change and achievement and risk&amp;#8221;. The idea is that we fear taking risks even though the cost of failure in today&amp;#8217;s world is much lower than it was when we developed such an aversion to avoid fatal events. In this model, human beings are resistant to change and want to preserve stasis. I think less attention has been paid to the flipside of this phenomenon which is that while we are loathe to change our own behavior, we are especially attuned to changes in the behavior of our environment. In other words, we like to pay attention to stuff that is changing or stuff that is slightly novel because small changes in our ancestor&amp;#8217;s environment might have signaled the arrival of a predator or food source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, of course, our environment is awash in constantly shifting stimuli, best embodied by the &amp;#8220;stream&amp;#8221; of Facebook or Twitter. This is stuff that is really easy and satisfying to pay attention to. On the other hand our work often consists of little or no external stimuli. My work consists of a computer screen of static text which changes not one whit until I take some action. This is the horror of the writer&amp;#8217;s blank sheet of paper a lack of stimulus that thousands of years of evolution has geared us to ignore in favor of whatever new images or ideas are flickering by elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Grocery List Workflow</title>
   <link href="http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/02/list-workflow.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://benchinn.com/blog/2011/08/02/list-workflow</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://byportmanteau.com/' title='Listary — Sync Your Lists'&gt;Listary&lt;/a&gt; is a terrific little iPhone app that has enabled a terrific workflow for putting together my grocery list. Basically it allows you to easily create checklists which can be synced to the cloud via &lt;a href='http://simplenoteapp.com/' title='Simplenote. An easy way to keep notes, lists, ideas, and more.'&gt;Simplenote&lt;/a&gt;. The best part for me is that the app can take any text file and turn it into a checklist with a checkbox for each line. So, here&amp;#8217;s my workflow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a grocery list file which then gets synced up between Simplenote, Listary and &lt;a href='http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/' title='nvALT 2.1 - Notational Velocity Fork'&gt;nvAlt&lt;/a&gt; on my Mac.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Get an email from my wife including some more items to put on the list. Add those items to the list in nvAlt.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Go to the grocery store, open up Listary on my iPhone and see all the items I need to buy as a checklist that I can check off as I go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>